# Utsav Deep

## SUMMARY

Test Associate with over 2.5 years of experience specializing in automation testing. Proficient in a variety of modern automation tools and programming languages including JAVA, Selenium, Cucumber, Appium, and other test automation tools. Demonstrated ability to design and improve test automation frameworks and drive efficient, reliable results. Committed to maintaining technical skills and up-to-date industry knowledge.

# Work Experience

## Test Engineer

January 2022 - Current

Bangalore, India

Intact Green Services (IGS)

- Promoted from Test Associate (1 year and 11 months) to Test Engineer due to demonstrated technical proficiency, alignment with company visions, and commitment to quality assurance
- Utilized SerenityBDD, Selenium, RestAssured, Cucumber framework with Java to automate over 40
   End-to-End tests along with integration and functional testing
- Implemented NodeJS based server routes to interact with CloudWatch Logs to verify backend functionality and automate component level tests
- Established a robust **mobile device testing automation** framework using **Appium**, contributing to the enhancement of testing efficiency and effectiveness.
- Played a key role in the proof-of-concept for two online payment applications by creating and executing API tests using TestNG and RestAssured

#### **Trainee Consultant**

July 2021 - December 2021

Intact Green Services (IGS)

Bangalore, India

- Successfully automated over 300 regression tests using the Selenium/WebDriver framework, significantly reducing the time needed for regression test execution
- Set up a proof-of-concept CI pipeline with Jenkins and GitHub for automatic test execution and email alerts for better observability.
- Trained manual testers on WebDriverIO and SerenityBDD, promoting a team-wide approach to test automation.
- Collaborated with manual testers for functional testing by creating and running functional tests and logging defects using Jira, Testrail, and Browserstack.

## Intern

June 2019 - August 2019

Bangalore, India

Cushy.com

- Collaborated with the marketing team to **gather potential customer data** from platforms like Google and Zomato, enhancing our customer outreach.
- Gained insights into **client and team management** by shadowing the Marketing team leader, which included learning the art of making effective cold calls.
- Conducted cold calls to pitch sales to potential customers, successfully onboarding them onto our app.
- Undertook field visits to local businesses for onboarding and provided demos of our application, demonstrating its
  potential to aid their growth.

# **EDUCATION**

## Presidency University

August 2017 - May 2021

Bachelors of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

Bangalore, India

## SKILLS

- Languages: Java, Javascript, Python, SQL
- Tools: Intellij Idea, Postman, Appium Studio, Docker
- Frameworks: Playwright, WebDriverIO, SerenityBDD, Appium, Selenium, RestAssured, Cucumber, NodeJS, AWS SDK
- Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Collaborative Nature, Goal-Oriented, Attention to detail